<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>blog.melvinzhang.net - web</title><link href="https://blog.melvinzhang.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.melvinzhang.net/feeds/web.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.melvinzhang.net/</id><updated>2008-01-22T15:38:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Websites</title><link href="https://blog.melvinzhang.net/websites" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-01-22T15:38:00+08:00</published><updated>2008-01-22T15:38:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Melvin Zhang</name></author><id>tag:blog.melvinzhang.net,2008-01-22:/websites</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My first website was started in 1999 after my 'A' levels but before I was enlisted. It was a very simple web site written by hand using HTML and CSS. The purpose was to learn HTML but it also served as a page which I would put up mini reviews …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My first website was started in 1999 after my 'A' levels but before I was enlisted. It was a very simple web site written by hand using HTML and CSS. The purpose was to learn HTML but it also served as a page which I would put up mini reviews of freeware games/applications. The main page also contains a number of dated entries to indicate when the site was updated and some snippets of what I was doing in real life. The last entry which was dated August 9, 2000 was posted on National Day, see below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/2008/01/22/websites/11636394-media_httpmelvinzhang_nxEki.png" width="500"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next period in my web authoring experience was when I entered NUS in 2002. All SoC students are given a web site at &lt;a href="http://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/%7Eunix_user_name"&gt;http://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~unix_user_name&lt;/a&gt;. It was far easier to setup a webpage than on my previous hosted service as I could upload the files to the server directly. I mainly used it to host a number of files, such as presentation slides etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2005, I started a server for ACM/IOI training. The server hosted the Mooshak contest management system and a DokuWiki based website for the ACM/IOI community in NUS. The site grew over the years and over time I starting using the site to document my HYP project and to create web pages for courses I was teaching. After a while, the server began to show signs of instability. Intending to avoid the hassle of managing a physical server, I requested for a Solaris Zone account from the school, which is now the hosting the current algorithmics.comp.nus.edu.sg site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="web"></category></entry></feed>